Let's train our first machine learning model.
让我们训练第一个机器学习模型
For linear regression, we need a continuous variable as our target.
对于线性回归 我们预测的目标是连续变量
So let's build a model to predict number of tags a question has.
那么我们来构建一个模型来预测问题的标签数量
We can write a simple UDF to split the text into a list and get the number of elements.
我们可以写个简单的 UDF 把文本拆分成一个列表并获取列表中元素的数量
So, we will try to predict the value in the non-text column.
我们的预测结果会存在 NumTags 列中
Our first question has five tags as we saw it earlier.
正如我们之前看到的 第一个问题有五个标签
Let's take a quick look at the distribution in this num txt column.
我们快速浏览一下这个 NumTags 列中标签数量的分布
Question seems to have between one to five tags.
问题有一到五个标签
T being the most common value.
3 是最常见的值
The next step is to decide what features you would like to use.
下一步我们要确定用哪个特征做预测
My first hypothesis is that for example the length of
我的第一个假设是 问题内容描述长度
the body of the question might be a good one since the longer the question,
可能是个好的选择 因为问题越长
the more topics it might cover.
它涵盖的主题可能就越多
Let's see if the data supports this idea.
让我们看看数据是否支持这个想法
Looking at the average lengths grouped by the number of tags,
按标签数量对问题内容平均长度进行分组
we see that indeed questions in more tags tend to be longer.
我们看到标签越多的问题往往更长
We could continue this exploration,
我们可以做更多探索
but for the sake of time let's just go with the single future.
但时间缘故 让我们只用这一个特征吧
First, we need to convert body lengths to a vector with the vector assembler
首先 我们需要使用 VectorAssembler 把内容长度转换为向量
since machine-learning models need features to be this vector type.
因为机器学习模型需要特征是向量类型
Let's just check this new column we created lengths feature.
我们来看看我们新建的 LengthFeature 列
It's indeed and dense-vector in this one value in it.
现在它已经变成了 densevector 里面还有这个值
So this looks good now.
看上去不错
So now we can define our actual linear regression model.
现在我们可以定义线性回归模型了
We could just use the default parameters or specify a few of them.
我们可以使用默认参数或指定其中一些参数
Since we only have one feature,
由于我们只有一个特征
let's just try to fit the slope but not the intercept of this linear regression model.
让我们试着拟合这个线性回归模型的斜率先不管截距
Our dataframe has a lot of columns at this point and
我们的 dataframe 现在有很多列了
we only really need the number of tags and the length feature.
但我们只需要标签的数量和长度这个特征列就够了
So we'll just create a data frame that only has
那我们就创建一个只有的
our target or label and the features we would like to use.
目标或标签以及我们要用的特征列的 dataframe
All right.
好了
So we have this dataframe called data with
Dataframe 创建好了
the labels and our lengths feature is the features.
只有 标签列和 特征列
Now let's just split this linear regression model on a dataset.
现在我们用这个线性回归模型来拟合数据集
Once the training is done,
训练完成后
we can get certain parameters of this model so we can see the coefficients for example on
我们可以得到这个模型的某些参数 例如 截距的系数
the intercept we decided not to be the intercept so that remains zero, it's expected.
由于我们没有拟合截距 所以它依旧是零 这是和预想一致的
We can also get the summary of this model.
我们也可以得到这个模型的摘要
The summary has virtual information for example
摘要有关于模型的部分信息
the root mean square error of the model log or how many iterations we actually have done.
比如模型的标准误差或者模型的迭代次数
But let's just take a look at the R-squared value we have here.
我们先来看看R平方值
So, for this very simple model that became down on our whole dataset,
因为我们用于拟合数据的模型非常简单
we have an R-squared of about 0.482.
我们的 R 平方约为 0.482
That's not really great, but we haven't done
效果一般般 但我们在
too much work on feature engineering and perimeter tuning.
特征工程和参数调优上基本没花时间
So, as a first pass.
第一次的尝试
Let's just stop it here.
我们就到这里吧